or whatever.
And so what I do is I just adjust the
training. The meat of the training,
how to do a check is the same,
but then I just adjust it to whatever
system they're using.
This is a huge thing. Over the last month,
I've had many locations reach out asking
about what they should use.
And what I've been telling them is hold
tight, use whatever you're using for now,
but hopefully soon we're going to have
something internal.
and we're going to mitigate to that or
migrate.
My big thoughts on that,
we've done this before.
I know Jay probably remembers,
but we used to have Pronto forms and they
piloted it in there and Texas was the
biggest user.
Yeah.
But the problem with it is they loaded
everything in there and it became such an
overwhelming form that nobody wanted to
use it.
When you say everything,
do you mean every single little question
And...
that can be asked per zone?
Was it was a different thing you had to
And.
go down?
everything you could ask with the
irrigation system.
What size is the main line?
What size is the valve?
What type of controller?
How many stations? How old?
Because their thought was,
we want to have all that in one document.
And they had this thought that the
irrigation techs are just going to be
okay with skipping this and that.
But really with technology,
we've got to make it super simple.
And so I know you're getting a lot of
feedback.
I've seen some of those members on the
call coming up. I've talked to them.
I know that some of them are very
analytical and brainy and some are very
negative.
So I'm pretty sure you already kind of
gather how to get that feedback.
But the one thing
I really want to hopefully get to as to
where we can have two levels of these
reports,
one just for a simple system check.
And then another one for a full onsite
assessment.
I think that'll solve the need.
The simplified one is just for the
regular contract expected checks that
keeps it super simple.
And then the assessment one would be for
when we pick up a new property or when
we're starting to do irrigation
assessments for extra work.
And then that will give you both.
I shared with Jay. Go on.
So.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
The first one was on an existing system.
What did you call that? Not an assessment,
but the first one.
A simple PMI,
preventative maintenance inspection,
Okay, PMR.
just a simplified one. Basically it's,
you know,
what's the name of the controller,
how many zones,
then go through like what's wrong with
each zone.
Something super simplified that even the
lowest tech technician can use and it's
super easy.
I think the part that we have one shot to
get right is preparation for future
comings. I was connected with One Rock,
the ESG team,
which is the Bright View Investors.
And a lot of the questions they had is,
how can we increase revenue with our
national accounts and all of our accounts?
by doing assessments.
So I think their angle is going to be,
we're going to start to push,
our teams can do in-depth irrigation
assessments and use that as a foot in the
door for our ESG,
but also for our revenue and growth.
The concern I have with that is currently
how we do that or how I do it with my
areas.
is I quarterback it with the text to
gather the field information.
They send it to me wherever I am in the
world, and I manually create a report.
And so if they're going to push that,
I think we're going to get a bottleneck.
And so that's why I think if we can do
the simplified one,
we're going to have success with the
teams.
And if we can do a more in-depth one,
we're going to...
really capitalize on revenue growth.
And I don't know how it's going to look,
but I always picture a report coming out
like the QSA.
got the fluff pictures and stuff like
that.
At least, I mean,
the report aspect could go with the
assessment report.
The other one can be whatever.
Okay.
Burns.
Sorry, I'm thinking.
Hmm.
Have you used any kind of mapping systems?
Yeah.
Yes, so...
Do something like this like Esri or
anything like that.
So with the mapping,
obviously the biggest challenge is the
subscription and then who owns the data
and all that stuff.
The most useful and most effective,
unfortunately, has been Google My Maps.
Google My Maps has proven to be the
Fisher Price that I can get anybody with
any technology level to utilize.
But not only that,
it's really easy to export the KML or the
data file,
get it into Salesforce under the maps.
And then it's really,
it works really great with our teams.
So they create the map and with my maps,
you send a link.
And so what I've got some branches doing
for every property,
they have a spreadsheet.
They got the property and then right next
to it is the map link.
So the irrigation tech has access to that
sheet with a link and on their phones,
they click the link,
the map opens up and they can GPS right
to it.
And so if we could find a way to create
that system or I
That's the best, easiest way. I mean,
again,
I've seen all these mapping systems.
Everybody's trying to sell it.
Everybody's got the latest and greatest,
but my biggest concerns are the
subscription cost,
the ease of use for my teams,
and also who owns the data, right?
Um...
A lot of these controllers like
WeatherMatic and WeatherTrack do mapping.
And I'm trying to work with them to
create an export function to where we can
get that data and get it into Salesforce
so that when we have branch turnover,
irrigation tech turnover,
it's all right there.
And are those are the weather track and
weathermatic are they are they GIS mapped?
So you have specific locations per valve
clock.
Yeah. Yes. So with Weathermatic,
they're a bit of a pain in the ***.
I don't think they're a viable team in on
that.
Weather track is a little bit more
forgiving.
They're working on putting in it where we
can export that. But in a perfect world,
if we could find a way to have an
internal bright view
system that mirrors Google My Maps and
does what it does,
I think we've hit a home run.
I've rolled it out with some of the most
stubborn people with technology.
In Vegas market, there's this guy, Leo.
He hates technology,
but I showed him this and showed him how
easy it was, and he's just taken off.
So he's actually on his weather track
clocks. He's creating the GI. No.
No.
No, on Google My Maps.
Oh, Google My Maps. Okay,
not not our track system. Okay. Yeah,
Google My Maps. It's very simple.
Our clients love it too.
Whenever I use it,
I do a virtual site walk with these large
proposals.
It wows them because you got pictures in
there.
Yeah.
I can create irrigation books where I
send them the link and it's in real time.
Yeah.
Yep.
But on the reports,
do you think it's possible to create
those two levels? I think, you know,
obviously we want to build this and roll
it out and have some success.
I'm just concerned like with the
different levels and knowing what I know
about these techs and their level of
technology.
I really think we need the simplified
system check one and then more in depth.
****.
Yeah.
And that mirrors my BrightPath training,
because for Tech Zero and Tech One,
I'm teaching them simple checks,
broken pop-ups and stuff like that.
Tech Two and above,
I'm teaching them more in-depth
assessments and how to identify revenue
opportunities.
I need to take your training.
Where are you at?
What part of town or what part of the
country?
I'm in Georgia.
Oh, well,
hopefully maybe soon I'll be out there.
You.
I know I've had some talks once I get New
Jersey done, then we'll shift out,
but yeah.
Can I do it on Absorb?
Just sign up for it and go through,
do you have the,
is there like a class online kind of
Um...
thing?
Coming really soon is Irrigation Tech
Zero. Right now,
our learning development team is
finalizing it. There is one in there.
There's a module in there on PMI,
so you could take the basic of the basic
one there when we launch it.
There should be a huge announcement.
I.
But I know with this,
I like to do more hands on,
like with the tech one and the simplified
version, we cover a lot of the stuff.
I show some pictures, but tech 2,
I do it in the field.
I take them out to the field and just
show them how easy it is to spot
everything.
Wright.
Now,
we're potentially rolling it out in July,
right?
Yes.
Are and are we thinking piloting pocket
areas, obviously?
Yeah, piloting, but but at branch level.
Okay.
Well, whenever it's about to launch,
if you touch base with me,
I can kind of help formulate a training.
and work closer with them.
And I think that's gonna be the key,
developing it and then getting the
training going and getting everybody up
to speed.
James,
we got you hooked in for this whole
process. So, you're going to hear,
you're going to hear about it before that
That's good.
happens. So,
We've we've scaffolded some.
We're using a part of Salesforce with FSM
called assets,
and we have a hierarchy of assets
starting at the clock,
Okay.
a sibling of a backflow,
and then we have under the clock you have
zones,
and then under zones you have the
different components that are involved in
that zone, so valve or...
Had or whatever now.
In order to fill out this form,
we don't have to have an asset
necessarily all the way filled out. Now,
I think that's going to be preferable in
the future because then you can add to it,
you can take away from it,
you can see the past history of each
asset.
With this also is exposing it through
native GIS,
which is something that has been in
Salesforce for two years now.
And they partner with Esri and ArcGIS.
So even on the mobile app in the field,
you could pin where a valve is and it'll
collect the GIS information and then you
can fill in information for it. Next week,
With that, with that,
can I ask one question?
what's that?
Will they have the ability to put a pin
at a at a desktop?
Yeah.
Yes.
Okay, yeah,
because that's one of the challenges I
Yeah.
found is our cell phones are fantastic,
but when they get into the field,
there's a lot of important sites where
their signal is just junk.
Yeah.
And so what I've been having them do for
that is put it on a map and when you get
By.
to the office, put a pin.
So they can pin it in the field on a map
offline.
Okay.
Okay, because it's not,
you're not using a cell signal,
you're using a satellite signal.
And then if you don't have the SAT signal,
you can still pin it.
Okay.
and fill in the GIS information or leave
it missing.
You can get close to where it is and it
can just be a pen without a geo mark to
it.
So this sounds kind of like a bit of an
in-depth.
Ohh.
Kind of site assessment irrigation book
type tool.
Which, in a...
Well,
the idea is you can switch off of that
and just go through a system and have
call outs on zones.
Okay, so it sounds like it's already dual.
You can go in-depth, assess,
So, more of a...
and then simplified.
That's where I've been headed with all
the research that I've been doing.
And so it's good to hear your feedback so
far. That's why I've been kind of quiet.
Okay, perfect.
Because I think you're going to be very
excited about where we're going with this.
And Jay hasn't even seen it yet.
All the work that I've we've put in so
far. But next week,
you're on a call that we invited you to.
I'm going to be I'm going to be
introducing this on that call. The I mean,
Yep.
we're going to we're going to start with
the basics.
And that's a dictionary and a shared
understanding of the different components.
OK.
making sure that we're covering every
component that we need to.
And this is not,
we're not talking about a form like we
tried the first time where you're filling
out all this stuff. Now,
there's a place for that on systems that
need to be documented, need to be mapped.
that you're continually going back to
that are heavily managed, where you need,
you know,
15 clocks mapped on a site and know where
all their zones are, et cetera.
And you're working from a beginning of an
as-built and you develop that into a
digital map. That's that assessment.
category,
but it needs to be as simple as just
going to a property like Michael Trinidad
with Victoria Gardens in Florida.
They just go there.
They might have a reference map that they
do,
but they have to they have to assess
every single residence in this community
on a quarterly basis.
Yeah.
They have 1100 homes. They have to
generate a report on.
And each home might only have one zone.
And the clock isn't on the home.
It's a master clock on a pod.
And so they'll know where the zone is and
what clock it is.
So all they have to do is collect, okay,
it's clock A,
and it's zone 15 for this house.
And we did these adjustments. There's no,
there's no breaks, there's no problems.
Boom, move on to the next one.
They bring it up and there might be a
break or something.
They do a call out on that break,
which becomes an item to be on a repair
list.
Then they move on to the next one,
so the thinking is, yeah.
I love that. I could...
I love that I could share a 500 page book
where I did that with a site that has 400
homes and that was all manual.
So I love hearing that.
So, I mean, it sounds,
it sounds like we're in the right,
going the right direction.
Matt.
Yeah, I think we're aligned.
The other two questions I have is how are
we looking?
Because originally one of the talks was
with these contracts,
they have contract expected checks and
they would be put into FSM as tickets,
more kind of like accountability and
nudges. Is that still a,
I think the biggest lift is going to be
Mmh.
how do we get existing contracts updated
with that?
Yes.
So that is the entry point for this is a
challenge because if we have a service
appointment that's generated for a
service contract and field service
management, that comes out,
it's assigned to an irrigation tech,
they bring it up,
on the mobile app and they have the
appointment information,
but right now all it's showing is
irrigation startup or irrigation
evaluation.
There's no other asset for them to look
at right now.
We do have a way of attaching documents
at the
property account level that go to every
single service appointment that's in the,
that gets generated from the service
contract. So right now, today,
we could add a map to that document and
it would show up on the mobile app so
that at least they would have a reference
if there's a PDF map or, you know,
an output from my.
my Google Maps or something like that.
And even a link,
you could have a link to my Google's map
potentially.
Perfect, that.
That exists today.
The idea of this is when it is an
Yeah.
irrigation type, work type,
that it also brings up the asset of the
property that has an irrigation system
related to it.
Getting those assets set up for each
property account is the big lift for this
project.
So there's got to be a simple entry point
to where that's not required in order to
Oh yeah.
start collecting data on a system.
So the idea I have so far is if there is
no asset yet,
you can actually start creating one in
the field.
Um...
So they could knock out to, you know,
instead of writing it out on or drawing
Okay.
it on a sat map, a printed out, you know,
piece of paper and they're marking the
zones on there, where the clock is,
where the backflow is, approximately.
They could be doing that on,
I'm thinking preferably on a tablet.
But it could be on a phone.
Um...
Yeah, tablets are a whole other thing. Oh,
I love that because we can get them
onboarded and then I can work branch by
branch and get them all up to speed in a
phased plan, which I think is great.
The tablet thing I have a little bit of a
concern with,
just because when we came over and
transitioned,
I know that all the techs had tablets and
what they found was they had tools.
But they were all sitting underneath the
seat, collecting dust.
Yeah.
And so what the,
I've had branches all over reach out
about tablets and I've kind of done an
evaluation to see if this is just a cool
thing to have or if they're actually
going to utilize it and then selecting
key people at the branch to utilize the
tablet versus the phone,
just to try to protect our investment and
the asset on that. The other question I,
kind of head on that is once this is up
and rolling,
I assume there's like with QSA,
you get QSA reports, who's completed,
who hasn't.
Would I be able to have access to kind of
where they're at on the performing on the
checks so that I can help be the
He.
accountability and the driver of getting
this done? Again, this is our
Our revenue here, and so...
The.
of accountability could happen. So if,
so here's number one that needs to happen.
The branch needs to be using field
service management.
Yeah.
They need to be assigning the service
appointments to the techs, to the crews.
When the crew completes that work,
you know who completed it.
by default.
There's no extra field to fill out.
There's, I mean, it was assigned to them.
They're the ones that did it.
They're the ones that completed it.
You have the whole hierarchy there.
You know what property it was on.
You know if it came from a service
contract or from an extra work sales
order.
You know if it was an emergency work
order that doesn't have anything linked
to it yet.
So all three of those things are handled.
And you know who did it.
So you can determine the volume of work
That's.
that a tech is doing based on the service
appointments that are assigned to them
and the number that they complete.
You're speaking my language.
I just had a conversation with Tony out
here,
the SVP or whatever his position is now
about how we've been horrible about that.
The one...
The one amazing,
maybe fantasy idea that we had talked
about was this communicating with extra
work. And when they submitted it,
it would generate an SO or a proposal
that the manager could adjust and assess.
Is that,
or did we come up with a game plan or a
path there? Because when I last spoke,
it was
Will see.
This first version is going to generate a
report that goes to, by default,
it goes to the account owner of the
property,
but we can adjust that based on our
discussions going forward if there is an
irrigation manager at the branch that
handles all of the extra work proposals.
But there's still going to be a step
where it's generating and giving you
everything that needs to be called out
and repaired.
And then they have to go into extra work
and complete the and create the SO to get
approved. It's not.
Gotcha,
so they didn't figure out a way to
integrate automatically?
Nope,
we have the integration of the extra work
spitting out a service contract of when
the repair needs to be done and it's
approved. That part is there.
But talking back to extra work, no.
Hey, if we could figure that out,
we would knock out the majority of our
problems and I think and really be
efficient. And probably to be honest,
probably too efficient.
We'd probably get buried.
I mean,
we heard that from Alex Chavez yesterday.
You know,
pretty much he's the paper pusher.
Yeah.
Although a lot of the paper he pushes is
trying is is wrangling and organizing the
output of the inspections and getting
them set up.
So we can take half of that work off of
off of the folks who are handling this
stuff. It's a good place to.
That works, 'cause what?
Or, maybe.
That works because one of the things I
had conversations with Jeff Robinson is
unifying the HR job codes and job titles.
And so obviously irrigation managers
would be ideal,
but salary wise or skill wise,
probably not going to happen.
But looking at utilizing the senior
irrigation tech position,
That's a great one.
I'm working on that BrightPath training
and that could be included in there and
kind of tying into this and managing that
type portion, if that makes sense.
So let me ask you some of those higher
authority questions.
So if we had a library of terms
nationwide,
Who would be responsible for that?
Who has the authority to change that?
Does it need to be?
regionalized or can we actually have a
standard irrigation terminology across
the country?
So I would try to take ownership of it.
I've had conversations with Dozier and
Robinson about expanding and supporting
the entire. So I mean,
I'm just waiting on the official thumbs
up. I would take that.
Here's when I came into this role,
I always heard irrigation is different
and everybody hung their hat on.
all this region is different than that
region.
And the method they apply irrigation in
the piping material and the approach is
different, but the principles are not.
And so when we talk about a dictionary,
the dictionary and that type of thing are
the same everywhere, right?
Some may use winterization, some may not.
And so
Okay.
I feel like sometimes we get lost in the
forest to the trees with this difference
part and having gone from Hawaii to
Seattle to Denver to Texas to the East
Coast,
there's unique differences on the way
they approach it at the branch,
but the terms and principles are the same
everywhere.
And if we stop making every region unique
and start creating a foundation of unity,
we can add their individual unique houses
on top of it,
and it's part of the One Bright View
model.
So to answer your question, yeah,
we can absolutely with the terms and
stuff like that, we can unify that.
And then, you know, next steps,
working with each market on their
specific approaches,
which is kind of what I've been trying to
build the system is getting that one
Yep.
BrightView foundation and then unity
amongst their own. Because in my vision,
every market should have a go-to
irrigation guy that's kind of driving the
culture and the market specific
information.
Okay. What kind of things do you adapt?
Well, I mean,
the adapting is we look at California.
California has a lot of spray heads for
planting beds,
or they have a lot of netafin.
We look at Denver and the Rocky Mountain,
they do a lot of winterization,
and they're only
going during seasonal.
And so the only thing that we really have
to adapt is the approach.
And then we look back east where the soil
is soft.
They may be doing vibra plowing or
sometimes they don't even need irrigation
as much.
And so it's just the piping material and
the approach that is adjusted.
Okay, so the local process.
But at the.
The local process at the end of the day,
it's still just water moving through
pipes.
OK.
Um...
What about...
So Alex brought this up yesterday around
regulations for reclaimed water and
things like that.
Are you are you training for those kind
of regional or nationwide regulations?
So I'm training the nationwide type stuff.
I'm training too.
Yes.
But then what I'm working with local
teams is building local stuff.
Like we look at New Jersey.
New Jersey has irrigation licensing that
you have to do.
So I'm working on building that.
Yeah.
It'll be like New Jersey specific.
Then with Texas,
they have irrigation licensing.
And so to answer your question,
we're addressing all that and trying to
figure out how to make all that specific
in the training and also utilize
BrightView University for that.
So like the teams in Texas could take a
irrigator license prep thing,
but they still have to go to a place to
take the test.
OK.
And with the reclaimed water,
there's a general base approach to
reclaimed water,
but then you also have to deal with the
governing authorities, like in California,
in the San Diego area,
in order to deal with reclaim,
you have to be reclaimed certified.
And that training is through the
the municipality agency.
And so kind of trying to identify those
pockets and figuring out how to support
them in prepping for the regulation
testing that is done by other people.
Okay.
So it's part of the plan we're building
out.
Jay, do you have any questions?
I don't. No,
looking forward to seeing the demo of
that assets that you're talking about.
So that'll be good.
The.
You know,
I think I can give you guys a sneak peek.
I just, I, you know,
I mainly want to encourage you, James.
Let me, let me pull this up.
Or,
or you can tell me I'm barking at the
wrong tree and I need to reset myself.
Alright, um,
and these are these are prototypes that
I'm about to show you, okay?
Yeah.
They don't get stuck up on pixels.
Can you see my screen?
Yep.
Wright.
That's.
So when you click into this,
you have details of that asset.
So what the name is,
it's a controller type, what its label is,
we can add the make model. Now,
none of these are required, okay?
So if you're going through and building
something in the field and you
and you click a pen on a map,
you can just say controller A and you're
done. And you just,
you have an indicator of what type it,
you know,
it's a controller and it's controller A,
and you can say it's here.
So it's not like the pronto form where
you're doing everything completely.
Plus with this,
it's repeatable every time.
When you go out to the property on the
next service appointment,
you're pulling up the same exact asset.
So whatever's been done in the past,
whatever callouts have been made in the
past, you have that history.
It's already there.
You don't have to fill it out again.
You don't have to say this clock has 16
zones because it's been completed. Now,
if it doesn't yet,
you can add it as you go or not.
You can just say zone 16, clock A,
has a lateral break or whatever.
So you have the asset information.
These are not as important.
And then you have everything that's
related to that clock.
So there's a backflow.
There's just a couple of zones I've added
in here.
But if you look at a specific zone,
you can just, I mean,
it has very basic information,
a zone number. And these are things that
that we're going to develop as a team,
what fields need to be here.
And this would be more like the
assessment.
You'd be dealing with this interface as a
manager, setting up a system,
setting up assets.
I'll show you what the mobile view ad hoc
will look like in a second.
And then you can see,
let me go back to the clock.
you click this hierarchy tab,
you can see the whole system,
the whole asset together.
So if this had 15 zones,
you'd see all of that.
If you had gathered the information in
the field, perhaps, you know,
one time you had to repair a valve,
and so you said, okay, zone one,
is the 1 1/2 inch PGA. You could do that.
Now, it's not required,
but it would be nice to have, potentially,
especially if you've touched it in the
past. You can give that level of...
granularity but it's not required.
Does that make sense?
Yeah, and I mean, I'm thinking ahead,
I would encourage him to have that level
of granularity because we talk about
proposing.
You know?
Yep.
But just think about the size of burger
that is, you have to bite, you know,
out of the gate. We just, we can't,
we can't have any blockers.
to using and actually filling out a form
at first. Like you said at the beginning,
we need a PMI.
We need something very simple.
And that's what Trinidad's doing in
Florida that works for them.
They got to generate this stuff.
They got to generate a high volume of
Yep.
this stuff.
We need to make it as quick and easy as
possible. So this is the beginning.
There's some things down here that we're
going to talk about.
When I say set up validation,
it's going through some questions.
If you do an assessment and start
building out this system,
think of it as like a guided walkthrough
to take you through in the setting up of
an asset.
And like I said,
it's not going to be a required thing to
have, but you can,
we have a way to stage you through
setting up an asset.
One question I do have,
and it may already be here,
but what I love in the QSAs is
opportunities for enhancement.
And what I'd love to have here is either
a notes box or something that documents
opportunities for enhancement.
Because one of the things I'm teaching
the guys is to go beyond what's broken
and visualize what could be and document
that. And if we have that in there,
Yeah.
which I assume you probably already do,
but because what I'm telling everybody is
for every controller,
you should have a list of...
upgrades or enhancements that the account
manager can use to build a relationship
with a client of trust.
Yep, I have that on my list.
For call outs,
not only for a repair that needs to
happen,
but for an enhancement that can happen.
Perfect, yeah,
because that's what I'm really pushing is
getting these technicians to look beyond
what's broken and what and be into what
could be because that's really going to
hit our growth,
client satisfaction and revenue.
And I'm sure you've talked to a lot of
irrigation professionals,
and I'm sure you already know this,
but I'm sure you've got a lot of requests
your way. But...
Um...
Some of them are a little wild,
I'm sure you've seen, right?
Uh...
Not necessarily, I mean.
Nothing more than I would have expected.
Not really surprised yet.
Okay.
I need to get surprised, I think.
Well,
I guess the reason I say that is
sometimes the irrigators come from left
field with suggestions that don't really
impact efficiencies or the goal. And,
you know,
I'm sure you already know some stuff you
can take it or leave it until later and
we can fine tune it.
Yeah.
That's not just irrigators, James.
That's landscapers. That's everybody.
Yeah.
Yeah, because...
Yeah, because like I said,
I talked to a lot of people and they're
just like,
everybody's got a different level of what
it should be.
And some of them are super analytical and
super left field.
And some of them are down to earth.
And I just,
we need the value of the teams,
but sometimes these managers are just,
they're not in tune with the actual
frontline workers. And so
Yeah.
I trust that you've got that filter where
you can say, that's a great idea.
We'll put it on the back burner and kind
of evaluate it.
That.
I always get nervous talking to the
managers because, I mean,
either they're going to talk about
BrightView's processes negatively or
they're going to come up with,
it'd be great to have this. But, you know,
one of the things having been here going
on 10 years in June,
I've seen a lot of systems and stuff.
And I've learned a lot of lessons from
that.
You know, and I'm excited for this.
I'm excited to jump in the trenches with
you and make sure that the rollout is
smooth,
make sure we get this going good and the
support is there because you guys will
probably do the technical support,
but I'll take on the task of doing the
usage support and stuff and get this
because I
I also believe this is a feather in the
cat for BrightView,
not only to announce and through
communications and for our clients and
our new bids,
but the success of it is actually
sticking with it.
Yeah.
Um, um...
What you described about taking
everything with a grain of salt,
that's my life.
You can ask Jay about that.
Um...
We're constantly having to discern
priorities. So that is my job.
And then I come back to guys like Jay and
other business leaders and say,
what do you guys rank this as?
So I'm definitely not the final say.
I document.
And then we make decisions about priority
and whether it's going to be a thing or
not.
And that's the way we handle our backlog.
Gotcha.
So this other view that I'm showing here
is the mobile app,
the field service management mobile app.
This is what a service appointment.
And again, this is a prototype.
It's not pixel perfect according to what
it even looks like today.
but it's pretty close.
So this is what a tech would get assigned
to them.
They're going out to do a quarterly
irrigation evaluation or a wet check or
whatever, even a repair potentially.
They're going to get all the information
from the asset.
If the asset's been set up on the
property account,
Then,
they're going to have this level of
insight. OK,
this is actually Esri GIS integrated with
Salesforce, so...
all the user licenses and all that taken
care of, James.
And you can create a new asset directly
from here,
but if you just want to look at clock A
for this asset, you can see this on a map.
This map is just mocked up,
so don't stumble over that.
But for each one of these,
this particular zone, three has,
Okay.
you can make a call out on it saying,
I have a broken head on zone 3.
And, you know, it's as simple as that,
is making a call out.
So if I look at Zone 8 and I want to make
a call out on it,
And this is not great UI yet. I'm just,
I'm gathering the components we need to
capture.
And that's the discussions that we'll
have when we look at this as a group.
If we look at it as a group,
that's to be determined yet, but.
Um...
So, you can say 5 broken heads.
You can also speak into this.
That's perfect,
because that's what I'm teaching them to
do that are struggling with spelling and
stuff.
Yeah.
So that's another call out.
So now we have 4 call outs in the system.
And it'll show each one that has a call
out.
They're in yellow here.
These are, this is the backflow,
so you know where the location of it is.
This is the clock,
so you know where the location of that is.
You see all the information for it right
now.
Programming is another layer that can be
here.
I don't know if this is the place for it
or it's another interaction.
in this actual Salesforce app that an
account manager or somebody else has.
I don't know if the program,
I saw it on your spreadsheet that you
actually have the program laid out there.
Do they actually fill that out?
And this is the program they have when
they leave the place?
There's there.
Yeah,
they're supposed to for a couple of
reasons. One,
so the account manager has it.
He doesn't have to tell the client,
I'll get back to you.
He can just look like a professional and
pull it up.
The other thing is I'm trying to get
ahead of these irrigation techs rushing
and screwing things up by doing schedules
wrong.
So what I'm training him to do is to get
it on paper.
And so, my thought is,
if we can have that in here.
And that's an easy way because then when
an attack or when an account manager
looks into it,
he should just be able to click the asset
and see the schedule, right?
That would be the idea, yeah.
So you could, if you're on a clock,
Yeah.
you click the clock and then you could
look at the program.
Yeah, so I'd like to have that in there,
especially for, you know,
making sure they put the right
information in.
I'm also working teaching them how to
control or program these controllers more
efficiently.
Okay. So if you don't have a map,
if you don't have anything in Esri yet
for this property account,
you can have a list of just the assets
that have been added in either on the
property account assets,
or this could be blank and a tech could
just come in and say,
add something, they could say,
I'm adding a controller,
and they could name the controller.
Um...
And then...
They could actually pin it if they wanted
to. This isn't even working,
but you get the idea.
So instead of having to have everything
laid out before they get there,
they could just go through and start
adding things.
And then if all they were going to do is
make a call out on controller D zone 16,
Those could be the only thing set up in
the system,
Yes.
and they could be done with their,
and they could submit this for repair or
for a result of an inspection.
So that's a very,
that's the very lightweight way of
getting onboarded with this.
You don't have to have the stuff set up
first.
Gotcha.
Is there an option to import like KML
files if we already have it mapped?
With Ezri, yes.
OK, perfect.
Yeah.
Now,
the ESRI piece of this is still up in the
air.
I've been learning and researching as
I've been working on this only for about
two weeks.
The.
I have the understanding and the path
forward for it,
but it is an enterprise license,
but it's like pennies compared to like a
Salesforce license. It's ridiculous. So.
We'll need to assess how many techs and
irrigation manager types.
There's a field worker who would be
interacting with these kind of things,
adding assets ad hoc. They could,
they for adding just the asset stuff and
not even interacting with Esri,
everything they have in their field
service.
management licensing covers that.
So you could do this,
you could do this all without even having
Esri as part of it,
if that becomes a thing.
There also is an opportunity to layer in
In a perfect world.
something like Mapbox or Google Maps as
an alternative to Esri.
So there's blocks.
If we could do that,
that'll be really wonderful.
If we could layer that in there,
that might save on the cost.
In a perfect world,
what my thought would be is obviously we
get a new property and all this stuff is
done within the first 30, 60,
90 but it's done by the senior tech or
irrigation manager.
That way, I mean,
those are the ones that would have.
The the licenses, I guess.
But that doesn't depend,
like not every tech,
if they're going to do a system check,
they don't need a license.
They can just be a user, right?
Correct.
Yeah, so I mean,
in a perfect world and where I'm headed
in the system we're trying to build is
you would probably have one to two people
at the branch that would be responsible
for doing this.
That would be the license holder.
Or all of that, and then the text could,
you know, just use it.
Me,
I don't know if you've ever seen this
before. I'm gonna drop a link into the...
Chat,
I would really like your your opinion and
feedback on that.
That's a like a specific ArcGIS solution
that they've built for irrigation
management.
Ah, yes.
Have you seen that before?
Yeah,
they reached out a year or two ago when
they came to this and we piloted it in
some areas.
And.
The general feedback is it was great,
but it didn't really work in all areas we
needed to. And when we went through it,
it was still in the development phases
and it kind of looked like crap.
They didn't have a lot of the icons
dialed in and stuff like that. And so.
The challenge I've always had with ArcGIS
is that it's just so damn expensive.
So with the way that we're using it and
the partnership that they have with
Salesforce, that changes some.
The.
This is an ESRI component that we drop
into the Field Service Management app.
This is like our quickest way to a win,
but the Mapbox or the Google Maps are
also an option.
Those will be completely custom.
But maybe in the long run might be better
for our organization for licensing and
cost, etc.
Yeah.
So, this is just a...
I'm working with the concept here.
I know that irrigation is spatial. So
Womack.
I've lived it too, James,
and having an idea of where things are
The.
and having a system mapped is battle
number one.
Yeah, we can't manage what we don't know.
And when it comes to these things,
Greg.
you know, my biggest challenge is,
unfortunately,
our irrigation techs are working off a
variety of reading levels and technology
levels.
And that's what I look for is specific
people who can navigate ArcGIS.
But then that's what I also liked about
the my maps is it's Fisher Price.
And I found that even the most technology
challenged. And so in my mind,
both options work and making sure that
the ArcGIS and the more technical stuff
is being utilized by those that are
prepared and actually doing it.
But we're also not leaving everybody
behind because that's kind of how we got
here.
Right? Oh,
they're not good with technology.
We'll just leave them alone.
And so I like both options because at the
Yeah, yeah.
end of the day, we need this information.
It's what they're being trained to.
We're expecting to get some growth.
And to be honest,
we haven't even scratched the surface on
our irrigation growth and revenue.
Yeah, well, yeah,
that that's why this is a priority.
Um...
This is our highest priority in FSM at
the moment.
Okay. I mean,
generally what you see so far,
am I barking up the right tree or am I
smoking something?
You're on the right track.
I like that there's different levels.
I like the simplicity of it.
And I'm also the mindset of we just got
to build something.
and get them going on it, you know.
But I like what I see. I like the usage.
and excited for like the rollout plan and
how we can get in front of the tripping
points that we have. You know,
I know one of the biggest tripping points
and why it's got to be kind of phased
rollout is a lot of our techs don't even
know their emails or the logins on their
phones. And so, you know,
Yeah.
once this is finalized,
Maybe we can connect and figure out a
rollout plan and kind of figure out that
stuff.
And I'd love to partner with you and
maybe we can record some training to go
in the irrigation track in Bright Path or
Bright View University.
that I can utilize and send them to,
and then I can do the hands-on training.
But once we get this done,
it's just rolling it out and getting past
the technology roadblocks and stuff like
that.
Awesome.
So you're reporting to Enrique right now,
is that right?
I actually, so I report to,
I don't know what their roles are,
the regional VP.
Whenever I'm working in a market or
Okay.
whatever, I connect with them.
And then it used to be the director of
operations.
So basically I report my goings on in
those areas with them and Enrico signs my
ETO and does all that stuff.
Okay,
so but there's potentially a point where
you're going to be reporting directly to
Dozier.
See, I don't know.
That's the question that we haven't
really figured out is what does that look
like and how it goes.
I would assume I'd be reporting to the
two east and west guys.
Mhm.
Well,
you might you might become like Jay who
But it's kind of a...
reports to my boss and becomes part of IT.
Yeah.
You know, we're doing all this work,
and the only way this works is if we try
to build 1 BrightView for irrigation.
We look at not only this portion,
Yeah.
but we look at procurement, we look at HR,
we look at talent acquisition,
we look at sales, all of these aspects.
There's no unifying thread supporting
each of those. And at some
point,
we've got to create that unifying thread
that supports all that,
but then builds off.
What we can't do is have the wild,
wild west.
I don't know your experience with the
branches, but I deal with at least 100,
Yeah.
if not more. And every time I step in,
it's like a new process, a new viewpoint.
And
Yep.
It's frustrating.
We need that uniformity of the foundation
that can be specialized for the branch
needs,
but we don't even have the uniformity of
the foundation.
Yep, Jay and I are very aware of that.
We just finished rolling out FSM to every
branch in the country.
Yeah, yeah. And so, I mean,
I'm going to keep doing what I'm doing.
The suggestion I got was just let it be
natural growth,
continue to work with the Midwest,
continue to work with until somebody
figures out who to give the thumbs up in
the official buy-in.
I know I talked to Jeff Robinson and he
was going to talk to his team and figure
out what that looked like.
Is there anybody else besides is on our
our list for that meeting next week?
Is there somebody in the Northeast or
somebody in the Midwest that you would
add to that team?
Uhh...
So the guy that I would have added in the
Midwest just left the company.
In the Northeast,
if you have thick skin and a passionate,
I have Eric Chadwick.
I don't know if he's on there.
He's been somebody that I've worked with,
but again, I say he's from New Jersey.
Is not.
So thick skin and you know he's
passionate. And then if we...
Did he work? Does he work for James Horn?
I don't know exactly who he works for.
I just know I've been working with him
and he got me in the door, so...
Okay.
Eric Chadwick and I don't know if Jay,
what his thoughts was about Steven
Portland, the irrigation manager there.
Yeah, I mean,
Steene might be a good addition as well.
What's his last name?
Greg.
K.
All right. All right. Thank you so much,
James. Thanks for, well,
you woke up early anyway, but.
Yeah. Thanks for doing this.
And thank you for navigating the
Hope your day goes well.
irrigator personalities.
I'm sure you've dealt with some of the
different personalities.
The irrigators have just unique
But.
personalities.
I've, I've, yes, and uh,
we're gonna get stuck in, so...
Looking forward to the progress,
the process, the path, the road,
whatever you want to call it. And
Yeah.
Well,
thank you for all your hard work and
I'll be.
passion. And just remember,
I'm here to help you guys succeed too.
So whatever I can do to help in the field
and with the teams make this a success,
I'm all in.
We can do this.
Awesome.